(
"ai_sub_version": "2.5.0",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 2,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 12,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"web_search_tool": "duckduckgo",
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": "libx264"
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
愛されないことは私が
That I wouldn't be loved...
一番知っていたの
...I knew it better than anyone.
それでもあなたはこの痛みに
Even so, you...
意味を与えてくれたから
...gave meaning to this pain.
壊れてしまう恋だとしても
Even if it's a love that will break,
信じたいと思えたんだよ
I was able to think I wanted to believe.
ヒトリ
Hitori (Alone)
あなたなら 私のすべて
If it's you, you're my everything...
わかってくれる気がした
...I felt like you'd understand me.
あなたを愛しすぎてしまう前に
Before I end up loving you too much...
あなたをすべて知る前に
...before I come to know everything about you.
空に願う どうか未来があるように
I pray to the sky, that there will be a future somehow.
今はそう 独り泣いてるの
Right now, yes, I'm crying alone.
小さな私の手に
In my small hands...
重ねた あなたの大きな手
...lay your large hands, overlapping mine.
失いたくないと願うほど
The more I pray not to lose you...
苦しくなっていたの
...the more painful it became.
唇についた 真っ赤な愛が
The crimson love upon my lips...
消える前に あなたに会いたくて
...before it fades, I wanted to see you.
目を閉じると 巻き戻される
When I close my eyes, I'm taken back...
最後の温かい夜
...to that last warm night.
優しいその目と 優しさと
Those kind eyes and that kindness...
言葉すべて 嘘じゃないと言いかせて
...tell me that all those words weren't lies.
これで最後の恋だと思うの
I think this will be my last love.
だから繋ぎ止めていたかったのに
That's why I wanted to hold on to you, and yet...
もうすべてわかってるから
Since I've understood everything now...
もう私に近寄らないでよ
Don't get close to me anymore.
果てしないこの 苦しみまでも愛せるほど
I can love even the suffering of this endless child...
強い人はいないから
...because there is no one as strong as you.
あなたを愛しているから
Because I love you...
ずっとあなたが私を忘れるまで
...until you forget me forever.
星に願う どうか叶えて
I wish upon the stars, please make it come true...
ずっと私のそばにいてほしい
...that I want you to be by my side forever.
あなたを愛しすぎてしまう前に
Before I end up loving you too much...
あなたをすべて知る前に
...before I come to know everything about you.
空に願う どうか未来があるように
I pray to the sky, that there will be a future somehow.
今はそう 独り泣いてるの
Right now, yes, I'm crying alone.
今もそう 独り泣いてるの
Even now, yes, I'm crying alone.
独りでいる この孤独が
When I was by myself, this loneliness...
いつから笑顔を振りまくことに慣れていた？
...from when did I get used to putting on a smile?
Lagu Tanpa Huruf R
Lyrics, Music: Nadya Fatira
Song Without the Letter R
*Tidak ada huruf R dalam lirik lagu
*There is no letter 'R' in the song lyrics
Ini kisahnya anak manusia
This is the story of a human child
Kau bisa memanggilnya dengan nama Iofife
You can call her by the name Iofife
Sebuah konsonan yang menyulitkan
A difficult consonant
Membuat lidahnya bosan tak bisa ucapkan
Making her tongue tired, unable to pronounce it
Dia coba pahami setiap manusia
She tries to understand every human
Punya hebat punya cacat
Has strengths and has flaws
Dia
She...
coba nikmati
tries to enjoy
hidup ini cuma sekali
this life only happens once.
Dia
She...
hanya punya modal cinta
only has the capital of love,
yang dia embuskan dalam setiap lagunya
which she breathes into every one of her songs.
Tak inginkan semua 'tuk suka
Doesn't want everyone to like it.
Dia
She...
hanya ingin tuliskan lagu
only wants to write songs
tentang semua yang ada dalam hatinya
about everything that is in her heart.
Bila tak suka tentu saja tak mengapa
If you don't like it, of course it doesn't matter.
Sejak kecil dia punya mimpi
Since childhood she had a dream
jadi musisi atau apapun di bidang seni
to be a musician or whatever in the field of art.
Tumbuh dewasa, bulatlah sudah
Growing up, it was final—
keputusannya 'tuk dapatkan mimpinya
her decision to achieve her dream.
Dia
She...
coba pahami
tries to understand,
setiap manusia punya hebat
that every human has greatness,
punya cacat
has flaws.
Dia
She...
coba nikmati
tries to enjoy
hidup ini cuma sekali
this life only happens once.
Dia
She...
hanya punya modal cinta
only has the capital of love,
yang dia embuskan dalam setiap lagunya
which she breathes into every one of her songs.
Tak inginkan semua 'tuk suka
Doesn't want everyone to like it.
Dia
She...
hanya ingin tuliskan lagu
only wants to write songs
tentang semua yang ada dalam hatinya
about everything that is in her heart.
Bila tak suka tentu saja tak mengapa
If you don't like it, of course it doesn't matter.
Dia
She...
hanya punya modal cinta
only has the capital of love,
yang dia embuskan dalam setiap lagunya
which she breathes into every one of her songs.
Tak inginkan semua 'tuk suka
Doesn't want everyone to like it.
Dia
She...
hanya ingin tuliskan lagu
only wants to write songs
tentang semua yang ada dalam hatinya
about everything that is in her heart.
Bila tak suka tentu saja tak mengapa
If you don't like it, of course it doesn't matter.
Hanya punya modal cinta
Only has the capital of love,
yang dia embuskan dalam setiap lagunya
which she breathes into every one of her songs.
Tak inginkan semua 'tuk suka
Doesn't want everyone to like it.
Dia
She...
hanya ingin tuliskan lagu
only wants to write songs
tentang semua yang ada dalam hatinya
about everything that is in her heart.
Bila tak suka tentu saja tak mengapa
If you don't like it, of course it doesn't matter.
Ioforia!
Obisa! Halo!
Obisa! Hello!
Aku Airani Iofifteen, Iofi dari hololive Indonesia
I'm Airani Iofifteen, Iofi from hololive Indonesia
first generation! Halo!
first generation! Hello!
Selamat datang di Birthday Live!
Welcome to my Birthday Live!
And by the way, the hashtag is #iofiLucidDream.
You can just tweet all of you can, okay?
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
So...
あのメンゲの皆は も知ってると思いますけど
I think everyone in membership already knows,
あの普通はギターは メンゲでしか弾いてないんだけど
but I usually only play the guitar in membership streams.
これがメンゲじゃない配信で初めてです!
This is the first time in a non-membership stream!
ちょっと怖いんだけど、まあまあまあ
I'm a bit nervous, but, well, well, well...
どうでしたか? どうどう?
How was it? How was it?
可愛い? 可愛い?
Is it cute? Is it cute?
いっぱいスクショ撮った?
Did you take lots of screenshots?
スクショ撮った?
Did you take screenshots?
I hope you enjoyed it!
And by the way, we still have a lot of more going on.
So after this, there's going to be a lot and lot of guests!
So please wait for it!
このあともゲストが盛りだくさんなので 楽しみに待ってて...
There will be plenty of guests after this, so please look forward...
...待っててくださいね! Don't forget to take screenshots!
...to it! Don't forget to take a lot of screenshots!
可愛い? Lagi?
Cute? More?
Lucu? Lucu? Lucu? Lucu?
Cute? Cute? Cute? Cute?
まあね 時間があれば これもね またギター弾きたいなと思っております
Well, if there's time, I'd like to play the guitar again.
はい!
Yes!
Okay, 準備オッケー オッケー オッケー オッケー
Okay, preparation okay. Okay, okay, okay.
Sip!
では ゲストパートにまた会おうね!
Then, let's meet again in the guest part!
Thank you! See you guys in guest part!
THERE IS A REASON
Lyrics: 岩愛理 Music: ヒグドライバー
Lyrics: Airi Iwata Music: Higdriver
どこから話せばいいんだろう
Where should I begin to tell you?
待ちくたびれても
Even if I get tired of waiting,
終わりだなんて言わせないから
I won't let you tell me it's over.
書きなぐった無意識の衝動をつれて
With the unconscious impulse that I scribbled down,
何かもかも壊したら
If I break everything,
不可能を始めればいいんだ
I can just begin the impossible.
There's a reason that we came across in this world
There's a reason that we caught the magnetic wave
傷つけ合う worldはどこへ
Where is the world where we hurt each other going?
空の果て 届くよう
Reaching the end of the sky,
愛のために泣けるのは
The reason I can cry for the sake of love
君がそこにいるから
Is because you are there.
君だけを呼び続け 歌うから
Because I will keep calling only for you and singing,
愛のために歌うのは
The reason I sing for the sake of love,
そして共に生きること
And living together,
ずっと ずっと 君と
Always, always, with you.
青色した空と波ひとつない鏡のような
The blue sky and the mirror-like sea without a single wave...
海を見ていた
...I was watching.
どんな場所に立って
No matter where I stand,
どんな形になって
No matter what form I take,
どんな時代にだって
No matter what era it is,
見つけ出すよ
I will find you.
いまをつづりにした さだめにさからって
Defying the destiny that has scripted the present.
There's a reason that we came across in this world
There's a reason that we caught the magnetic wave
引き寄せ合う 二人はどこへ
Where are we, drawn to each other, going?
愛のために進むのは
The reason I move forward for the sake of love,
君がここにいるから
Is because you are here.
僕だけが君を 守るから
Because only I will protect you,
愛のために願うのは
The reason I wish for the sake of love,
そして誰も傷つけずに
And without hurting anyone,
ずっと 隣で
Always, by your side.
僕らは越えていく
We will cross over...
すべての憎しみを
...all the hatred.
偽物の正義など
Fake justice and such,
捨ててしまえ
Throw it all away.
愛のために泣けるのは
The reason I can cry for the sake of love
君がそこにいるから
Is because you are there.
We will always...
Together...
愛のために進むのは
Moving forward for the sake of love,
君とここにいるから
because I'm here with you.
僕だけが君を守るから
Because I alone will protect you.
愛のために願うのは
What I wish for for the sake of love
そして共に生きること
is for us to live together.
ずっと...
Forever...
Believe...
Together!
うっほ！よっぴー！お誕生日おめでとう！
Whoo! Yoppii! Happy Birthday!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
やー、やった！今年も来てくれてありがとう！
Wow, yay! Thank you for coming again this year!
えー、どうもこんにちは。ときのそらです。
Ehh, hello there. I'm Tokino Sora.
よろしくお願いします。こちら。えへへ。
Nice to meet you. This way. Ehehe.
やー、なんかね、バラード歌っちゃったね。
Man, we really sang a ballad, didn't we?
ねー。
We did.
より... 私すごい気になってるんだけど...
More than that... I'm really curious...
なんなん、この...？
What's with this...?
宇宙、すっごい寒いから、これあったかいよ。
Space is really cold, so this is warm.
え、宇宙で焚き火なんてできるんだね。
Eh, you can actually have a bonfire in space.
できるよ、一応。
You can, sort of.
だって酸素があるってことだもん。
I mean, it means there's oxygen.
あ、でも酸素いるからさ、今、この、バリアあるから。
Ah, but we need oxygen, so right now, there's a barrier.
バリアあるからね。酸素ないから、
Because there's a barrier. There's no oxygen,
ないんだったら、もう燃えないじゃん。
so if there wasn't, it wouldn't even burn.
あ、ま、そう、そうだね。そうだね。
Ah, well, yes, that's true. That's true.
そう、あったかいよ、これ。
Yeah, it's warm, this.
よかった。なんか...
I'm glad. It's just...
MCでこんなにまったり焚き火の前で、こう、
Having an MC segment so relaxedly in front of a bonfire,
夜の、なんか二人で喋っちゃうみたいな雰囲気で、
in an atmosphere like two people chatting at night,
やることないよ。ないから、ちょっと変な感じがする。
we don't usually do this. So it feels a bit strange.
あ、そうだね。普通にさ、ポーズの後にさ、
Ah, you're right. Usually, after a pose,
「あー、やっと歌えたね！」っていう...じゃない？すぐ。
"Ah, we finally sang it!" is what we'd say, right? Immediately.
そうだけど、やっぱり今年のテーマ、もっとゆるいとか、
Right, but as expected, this year's theme is more relaxed,
落ち着く雰囲気欲しいから、そのダンスとお歌の後に、
and I wanted a calm atmosphere, so after the dance and song,
ちょっとマイクをね、ちょっと置いて、ここに座ってるっていう。ね。
we put the mics down and are just sitting here. Right.
でもいいね。なんかまったりできるから、
But it's nice. Since we can relax like this,
ちょっとのんびりしてお喋りできる感じ、いいと思う。すごく。
I think the feeling of chatting leisurely is great. Really.
えー、やったやった。
Ehh, yay yay.
でね、今年、誕生日に二回目ぐらい言ったんだよね、毎年。
And you know, this year, I've said this for my birthday about twice every year.
そう、今年... ん？去年？去年と一昨年ってこと？
Right, this year... Hm? Last year? You mean last year and the year before?
そうそうそう。今年で、来年も来る？
Yes, yes, yes. With this year, will you come next year too?
え、もちろんもちろん！呼んでもらえればいつでも行くよ。
Eh, of course, of course! If you invite me, I'll go anytime.
おー、やったー！
Oh, yay!
じゃあ、決定です。よろしくお願いします。やったー！
Then it's decided. Looking forward to it. Yay!
そしたら、なんかもう、この去年と今年も結構ハンドマイクでやってるから...
And then, well, since we've been using hand mics quite a bit last year and this year...
そうだね、なんか結構...
True, it's been quite a bit...
聴かせるみたいな感じの曲ばかりだったよね。そう。
The songs were all the type that you just listen to, right? Yeah.
じゃあ、来年はバリバリ踊ります？そしたら。
Then, shall we dance vigorously next year? If so.
踊る！うおー！
We'll dance! Whoo!
いいね。踊り、やっぱりね、そら好き、踊るの。
That's good. As expected, Sora likes dancing.
大好き！よっぴーは？
I love it! How about you, Yoppii?
好き好き好き！ね、いいよねー。
Love it, love it, love it! Right, it's great.
いや、でもさ、なんか今年のさ、テーマ先も聞いてバラードだって聞いて、
But, you know, hearing earlier that this year's theme is ballads,
やっぱバラードのさ、全体をさ、ライブするのってすごい難しいなって私は思っちゃうの。
I thought that doing a whole live show of ballads would be really difficult.
え、そうなの？ほ！
Eh, really? Oh!
やっぱ演出とかもそうだけどさ、
The production and everything, but...
やっぱ私はいつも dance とかで見せるみたいなのやるから、
since I always do things that show off with dancing and such,
バラードで挑戦するのってすごいなって思ってた。
I thought it's amazing to challenge yourself with ballads.
あー、そうだね。でもなんか自分にとっては、
Ah, I see. But for me,
バラードが一番声に似合うから。
ballads suit my voice the best.
そう、なんか、もっと見せたいなっては思ってて。
Yeah, so I was thinking I wanted to show that more.
あー、ね。
Ah, right.
そう... あ、ほら見える、いっぱい！うー！
Right... Oh, look, I can see so many! Ooh!
きれい！宇宙。宇宙に来ました。
Beautiful! Space. We've come to space.
あの、去年もちょっと行っ...
Um, last year we went a bit...
一応は宇宙に行ったんだけど、
We did go to space,
こんなにあまり見えないかもしれない、それ。だから、
but it might not have looked like this as much. So,
今年はちゃんと宇宙に行きたいです！
this year I wanted to go to space properly!
わー、すごい！宇宙来ました、二人で。すごい！
Wow, amazing! We've come to space together. Amazing!
あ、きれい、本当に！おー、
Ah, it's really beautiful! Oh,
なんかねーさんと似合うんじゃない？
doesn't it suit you, big sister?
本当？
Really?
そう、なんかイメージカラーが青だからね。
Well, since your image color is blue.
ほら、青のステージもこっちも。
Look, the blue stage and here too.
え、いいなー、かわいいなー。へへへ。
Eh, it's nice, it's cute. Hehehe.
みんなもいっぱい写真撮った？
Did everyone take lots of photos?
撮ったー！
I did!
似合うでしょ！ ほら！
It looks good on you! Look!
めっちゃ可愛い！ ふわふわして！
It's so cute! Sparkle sparkle!
おー！
Oh!
可愛い！
Cute!
うぉっ！
Whoa!
もっと見て！ あ！あ！
Look more! Ah! Ah!
これ私の記念日じゃないんだ
Wait, this isn't my anniversary.
そうだね！ ヤッピー！
That's right! Yippee!
ヤッピー！ ヤッピー！
Yippee! Yippee!
大丈夫だよ！ はい！
It's okay! Hi!
いっぱい撮りました！ 二人で！
I took a lot! With both of us!
ういー！ ういー！
Whee! Whee!
ということで今回まだまだいるので
So, there's still more this time,
皆さんも楽しみにしててください！
so everyone, please look forward to it!
ねえ！ 本当におめでとうだよー！
Yeah! Really, congratulations!
では来年また歌って踊ろうね
Well then, let's sing and dance again next year!
踊ろう！
Let's dance!
はい！ 皆ありがとう！
Alright then, everyone, thank you!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
また会おうね！ またねー！
See you again! See you later!
またねー！
See you later!
何度も問いかけた
I asked myself many times,
自問自答繰り返した先に
after repeating my inner dialogue...
答えがあるのなら
if there's an answer,
このまま探してみようか
should I keep searching like this?
あなたの未来図に
In your future plans,
私は少しでもいれたかな
was I even a little bit in them?
あなたのいない世界は
A world without you
想像さえつかなかった
was something I couldn't even imagine.
もしもあなたが
If you...
あの子を選んだ瞬間に
at the moment you chose that girl,
私が頭の中
if I was running through
駆け巡っていたのなら
your head then,
悔しいな
how frustrating.
こんなにもあなたのこと
Before I came to
好きになってしまう前に
love you this much,
せめてさ
at least...
さよならの言葉告げて欲しかったなんて
I wish you had told me goodbye.
勝手でワガママだよね
It's selfish and demanding, isn't it?
誰より想ってるのに
Even though I think of you more than anyone,
あなたを世界で1番笑顔に
the one who can make you the happiest
変えられる人はきっと
in the world is surely
私じゃないから
not me.
どうか幸せになって
So please, be happy.
どんなに願っても
No matter how much I wish,
変わりはしないこの現実が
this reality that will not change...
ただただ目の前の
just the light
光全て奪い去った
right before my eyes was all taken away.
生まれ変わっても
Even if I'm reborn,
もう一度あなたに恋するかな
would I fall in love with you once more?
そんな妄想なんて
Even such delusions,
考えることすらも馬鹿みたい
just thinking about them feels foolish.
こんなにもあなたのこと
Before I came to
好きになってしまう前に
love you this much,
わざとさ
on purpose...
優しい言葉で勘違いさせないでって
don't lead me on with kind words.
勝手でワガママだよね
It's selfish and demanding, isn't it?
あなたの幸せそうな
Your happy-looking face alone
顔を見るだけで胸いっぱいになる
fills my heart to the brim.
あなたと私はきっと
You and I are
お似合いじゃないから
definitely not meant to be.
どうか幸せになって
So please, be happy.
涙出るのは
The reason tears fall
嘘でも強がるから
is because I'm acting tough even if it's a lie.
気づかないふりしないで
Don't pretend not to notice,
どうしても諦められないよ
I just can't give up.
ほら
See...
こんなにもあなたのこと
...even this much, you're everything...
こんなにも
So much...
あなたのこと 好きになってしまう前に
Before I fell in love with you so much...
せめてさ
At the very least...
さよならの言葉 告げて欲しかったなって
I wish you had told me "Goodbye"...
勝手でわがままだよね
I'm being selfish and self-centered, aren't I?
こんなにも
So much...
あなたのこと 好きになってしまう前に
Before I fell in love with you so much...
せめてさ
At the very least...
さよならの言葉 告げて欲しかったなって
I wish you had told me "Goodbye"...
勝手でわがままをだよね
I'm being selfish and self-centered, aren't I?
誰より思ってるのに
Even though I care more than anyone...
あなたを世界で
in the whole world,
一番笑顔に
the one who can make you smile the most...
変えられるのはきっと
...is surely...
私じゃないから
not me...
他で幸せになってね
So please be happy with someone else.
幸せになって
Be happy.
あー！二人とも来てくれてありがとう！
Ah! Thank you both for coming!
お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy Birthday!
ありがとう！嬉しい！ありがとう！
Thank you! I'm so happy! Thank you!
イェーイ！
Yay!
嬉しい、ありがとう！おめでとう！
I'm happy, thank you! Congratulations!
でも最初は、誰から自己紹介する？
But first, who's going to introduce themselves?
んじゃ、俺から行こうかな。
Then, I'll go first.
あ！
Ah!
はい！ホロスターズ一期生の律可です！
Yes! I'm Rikka from Holostars 1st Generation!
よろしくお願いします！
Nice to meet you!
イェーイ！
Yay!
次！
Next!
ホロスターズグループ、UPROAR!!の夕刻ロベルです！
I'm Yukoku Roberu from UPROAR!! in Holostars!
よろしくお願いします！
Nice to meet you!
イェーイ！
Yay!
いやー、いい！一緒に歌ってくれてありがとう。
Man, that was good! Thanks for singing with me.
いや、こちらこそ！呼んでくれてありがとう！
No, thank YOU! Thanks for inviting me!
いやー、嬉しかった！ありがとうございました！
Man, I was so happy! Thank you so much!
律可パイセンとは、デビューのころお世話になってて。
Rikka-paisen really helped me out around my debut.
あー、一周年とか来てもらったりしたもんね。
Ah, you came for my first anniversary and stuff.
うん。なので、今回歌いたいなと思って。
Yeah. So I really wanted to sing with you this time.
あー、ありがとうね。
Ah, thank you.
呼んでくれてありがとう、で。
Thanks for inviting me, and...
ロベルくんは、ロベルくんは、
Roberu-kun is, Roberu-kun is...
後輩だもんね。
He's a junior, right?
後輩ですよ！
I am a junior!
そうそう、後輩よね！
Right, right, a junior!
なんか、スタジオで会ったときにさ、仕事で、
When we met at the studio for work,
たまたまキラッって... なんかこう、
by chance... like a spark...
来年の誕生日にさ、来てくれる？って
I asked, "Will you come to my next birthday?"
スタジオで本当にばったり会って。
We really just bumped into each other at the studio.
そう、ばったり会って言ってくれて、
Yeah, you asked when we bumped into each other,
まさか本当に呼んでもらえるとは思わなくて。
and I never thought you'd actually invite me.
え、逆に信じられなかったの？
Wait, you didn't believe me?
いや... もう嬉しすぎてびっくりしちゃったよ。
No... I was just so happy I was surprised.
いいえいいえ、ありがとう！
No, no, thank YOU!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
え、僕たちが揃うのが、2年ぶりだよね。
Wait, it's been 2 years since we were all together.
久しぶりだね。
It's been a while.
2年前のカウントダウンライブで、
At the countdown live 2 years ago,
この3人とコボちゃんと4人で歌ったんだけど、
we sang with Kobo-chan, the four of us,
一緒に歌うのは、実はこれぶり。
but singing together, it's actually been since then.
これぶり。
Since then.
久しぶり！
It's been a while!
2年前！
2 years ago!
そう、もう2年前。
Yeah, it's already been 2 years.
そう, 2年経ったんだなー。
Yeah, 2 years have passed...
ねー、2年だなーっていう感じで。
Yeah, it feels like it's been 2 years.
早いなー。
That was fast.
早い。早いですね。
Fast. It's fast.
でも一緒に歌えてめちゃめちゃ楽しかったです！
But I had so much fun singing together!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
いや、なんか3人バンドみたいだったね。
Man, we were like a 3-person band.
ギター一人！
One guitar!
ギター一人、あとタンバリンみたいな。
One guitar, and then like a tambourine.
見たことある感じの絵面だった。
It was a scene I've seen before.
じゃあ来年だったらもうバンドやりますよ。
Well, if it's next year, we'll do a band then.
バンドね。
A band, huh.
じゃあ僕ドラムやろうかな。
Then maybe I'll do drums.
ドラムやろうかな。
Maybe I'll do drums.
じゃあ俺、あのー、トライアングルやるわ。
Then I'll, uh, do the triangle.
あれ？なんで？
Wait, why?
イオフィは何やる？
What will Iofi do?
マラカス！
Maracas!
えー！ちょっと待って、リズム隊いらなくない？
Eh! Wait a minute, don't we not need a rhythm section?
リズム隊じゃん！
It's a rhythm section!
音聞こえないけど。
I can't hear any sound though.
ギターとかいないんだ。
So no guitar then.
えー、でもトライアングルとか思わなかったの？
Eh, but didn't you think of the triangle?
チーンってするときの。
For the 'ting' sound.
気持ちいいね、結構。
It feels pretty good.
タンバリンにしようかな。
Maybe I'll go with a tambourine.
タンバリンね。
Tambourine, huh.
タンバリンで。
With a tambourine.
みんなうるさい奴じゃん。
Everyone's just noisy then.
シャンシャンシャンシャン！
Shan-shan-shan-shan!
タンバリン、シャンシャンシャンシャン！
Tambourine, shan-shan-shan-shan!
今回は結構しっとりだったから。
Because this time was pretty mellow.
そうそう。
Right, right.
誰か分かんないですけど、さすがにこれは。
I don't know who it'll be, but surely, this is...
でもハモリ難しかったね。3人だから。
But harmony was hard. Because there's three of us.
男性と女性が、二人で歌う曲探すの難しくて。
It's hard to find songs for a male and female.
確かにね、キーがね。
True, the key...
キーが。女性の曲だったら下げなきゃいけないし。
The key. For a female song, you have to lower it.
そうそう。
Exactly.
男性だったらこっちが低すぎるし。
And if it's a male song, it's too low for me.
そう、低すぎて、
Yeah, too low,
だからどうしようと思って。
so I wondered what to do.
でもめちゃめちゃ素敵な曲！
But it's such a lovely song!
ね、原曲もよかった。
Yeah, the original was great too.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
よかったです！
It was great!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
最初は絶対に二人を招待したんだけど、
At first, I definitely wanted to invite you two,
その時期に曲まだ決まってなくて。
but at that time, the song wasn't decided yet.
あ、そうなんだ。
Oh, is that so?
後から決まったんだ。
It was decided later then.
後から。そう、後から。
Later. Yeah, later.
いいの見つけたね。
You found a good one.
ありがとう！本当によかったよ。
Thank you! It was really good.
声にも合ってたし、この3人の。よかった。
It suited our voices too, the three of us. It was good.
やったー、本当によかった。
Hooray, it was really good.
ゲストが決まって、その曲って感じで。
The guests were decided, and then the song.
なるほどね。
I see.
いや、でもまたやりたいけどね。
Man, I'd love to do it again though.
え、やりたい！
Eh, I want to!
バンドやりたい！ バンドやろうよ！ バンドやる？
I want to be in a band! Let's do it! A band?
バンド…あたしマラカス
Band... I'll play the maracas.
練習時間めっちゃかかりそうだけどね
It'll probably take a lot of practice time, though.
ドラムやってみたいからな えー？何の？
Since I want to try the drums. Eh? What's that?
やるなら練習しますよ
If we're doing it, I'll practice.
じゃ、来年やりますバンド 楽しみ！
Then we'll do the band next year. I'm looking forward to it!
本当にやりそうだから怖い 怖い
It's scary because you seem like you'd really do it. Scary.
ということで来年楽しみにしてね
So, please look forward to next year!
みんな本気にするよ みんな本気にしちゃうよ
Everyone's going to take you seriously. Everyone's really going to believe it.
怖い怖い じゃ来年楽しみということで
Scary, scary. Well, look forward to next year!
本当にみんな見てくれてありがとう これからもまだまだあるので
Really, thank you everyone for watching. There's still more to come after this,
楽しんでください 楽しんでね
so please enjoy it! Enjoy, okay?
おめでとう！ ありがとう！
Congratulations! Thank you!
ぼくらのレットイットビー
Bokura no Let-it-Be
Lyrics, Music: 計測器 (HarryP)
Lyrics, Music: Keisokuki (HarryP)
生まれ変われるのなら
If I could be reborn,
目印になるから 巻いておこう
I'll wrap it around as a sign.
小指と小指の長い糸
The long thread between our pinkies...
ほどけない様に 結んどこう
...let's tie it so it won't come undone.
夏祭り 陽炎 雨降り
Summer festival, heat haze, rainfall.
空に虹がかかる頃なのかな
Is it around the time a rainbow appears in the sky?
壊れた感情じゃ いつか君を消して行く
With broken emotions, someday they'll erase you.
見えなくなると失われる灯火
A light that is lost when it becomes invisible.
でも結んだ長い糸 ほどけ落ちていないから
But the long thread we tied hasn't come undone,
また僕たちは出会う時が来る きっと
so we will surely meet again one day.
僕ら大人になったら
When we become adults,
正義のヒーローになるんだ
we'll become heroes of justice.
地球の平和を守るのさ
We'll protect the peace of the Earth.
探検しようぜ お化け屋敷
Let's explore a haunted house.
でも本当は怖くて泣き虫
But the truth is, I'm a scaredy-cat and a crybaby,
一緒にいたいだけ
I just want to be with you.
明日も晴れて 空を仰いで照らせば
If it's sunny tomorrow too, and we look up and shine upon the sky,
僕らはここに秘密基地を作ろう
let's make a secret base here.
そして探検しよう 雨ならゲームしよう
And then let's explore, or if it rains, let's play games.
そんな時間が ずっと続くはずだったんだ そう
That time was supposed to last forever, yeah.
悪者は僕だった
The bad guy was me.
逃げたのは僕だった
The one who ran away was me.
嘘じゃない本当の嘘つきだ
It's not a lie, I'm a real liar.
花束に包まれて 目を瞑る君は
Wrapped in a bouquet, you with your eyes closed,
安らかに 清らかに
are peacefully, purely
眠っていたんだ
sleeping.
壊れた感情が いつか君を消して行こう
Broken emotions will someday erase you.
失う前に 消えてしまう前に
Before you're lost, before you disappear,
ただ結んだ長い糸 ほどけ落ちていなかった
the long thread we tied just hadn't come undone.
きっと僕たちは 出会う時が来る
Surely the time will come when we meet.
Pandangan Pertama
First Sight
Lama ku memendam rasa di dada
For a long time I've kept my feelings in my chest
Mengagumi indahmu, wahai jelita
Admiring your beauty, oh beautiful one
Tak dapat lagi ku ucap kata
I can't say a word anymore
Bisuku diam terpesona
My silence is stunned
Dan andai suatu hari kau jadi milikku
And if someday you become mine
Tak akan kulepas dirimu, oh kasih
I will never let you go, oh love
Dan bila waktu mengizinkanku untuk menunggu
And if time allows me to wait...
Dirimu...
For you...
Kurasa ku tlah jatuh cinta
I feel I have fallen in love
Pada pandangan yang pertama
At first sight
Sulit bagiku untuk bisa
It's hard for me to be able to
Berhenti mengagumi dirinya
Stop admiring her
Seiring dengan berjalannya waktu
As time goes by
Akhirnya kita berdua bertemu
Finally, we both meet
Oh diriku tersipu malu
Oh, I am blushing
Melihat sikapmu yang lucu
Seeing your cute attitude
Dan andai suatu hari kau jadi milikku
And if someday you become mine
Tak akan kulepas dirimu, oh kasih
I will never let you go, oh love
Dan bila waktu mengizinkanku untuk menunggu
And if time allows me to wait...
Dirimu...
For you...
Kurasa ku tlah jatuh cinta
I feel I have fallen in love
Pada pandangan yang pertama
At first sight
Sulit bagiku untuk bisa
It's hard for me to be able to
Berhenti mengagumi dirinya
Stop admiring her
Oh Tuhan tolong diriku
Oh God, help me
Tuk membuat dia menjadi milikku
To make her become mine
Sayangku, kasihku, oh cintaku
My dear, my love, oh my beloved
She's all that I need
Dan bila kita bersama
And if we are together
Kan ku jaga dirimu untuk selamanya
I will take care of you forever
Oh terima cintaku...
Oh, accept my love...
Summertime, ain't a summertime
If I don't have you as mine,
but you're always on my mind, yeah
In the magazine you showed up
Baby girl your beauty makes my mind blow up
Your personality it's calm and friendly
The kinda girl that I would love to be with me
Here's my cellphone number so please call back
Kurasa ku tlah jatuh cinta
I feel I have fallen in love
Pada pandangan yang pertama
At first sight
Sulit bagiku untuk bisa
It's hard for me to be able to
Berhenti mengagumi dirinya
Stop admiring her
Oh Tuhan tolong diriku
Oh God, help me
Tuk membuat dia menjadi milikku
To make her become mine
Sayangku, kasihku, oh cintaku
My dear, my love, oh my beloved
She's all that I need
Pesawat Kertas 365 Hari
365 Days Paper Airplane
Kutatap langit di pagi hari
I look at the sky in the morning
Kuawali hari dengan doa
I start the day with a prayer
Semoga satu hari ini bisa
Hopefully, this one day can
Dipenuhi oleh senyum
be filled with smiles
Walaupun terkadang hujan turun
Even though sometimes it rains
Dan air mata juga mengalir
And tears also flow
Di hari yang tak berjalan dengan mulus
On a day that doesn't go smoothly
Besok pun tetap semangat
Tomorrow, stay enthusiastic
Di dalam mimpiku selalu
In my dreams, always
Terlihat ada diriku sendiri
I see myself
Yang dengan bebasnya melakukan semua
Who freely does everything
Hal yang ingin aku lakukan
The things I want to do
Hiduplah bagai pesawat kertas
Live like a paper airplane
Terbang dan pergi, membawa impian
Fly and go, carrying dreams
Sekuat tenaga dengan hembusan angin
As strong as possible with the gust of wind
Terus melaju terbang
Continue to race and fly
Jangan bandingkan jarak terbangnya
Don't compare its flight distance
Tapi bagaimana dan apa yang dilalui
But how and what it went through
Karena itulah satu hal yang penting
Because that's the one thing that's important
Selalu sesuai kata hati
Always follow your heart
三百六十五日
365 days
Di saat terlihat bintang-bintang
When the stars are visible
Atau malam yang gelap gulita
Or a night that is pitch black
Pada saat semangatmu hilang carilah
When your spirit is gone, look for
Orang lain untuk bicara
Someone else to talk to
Manusia tidaklah pernah
Humans are never
Ditinggal sendirian saja
Left alone
Terkadang kita tak menyadari
Sometimes we don't realize
Hal baik di sekitar kita
The good things around us
Hiduplah bagai pesawat kertas
Live like a paper airplane
Terbang dan membawa cinta kita semua
Flying and bringing all our love
Sayap yang terbentang dengan percaya diri
Wings spread with confidence
Dilihat semua orang
Seen by everyone
Walau tak tahu cara melipatnya
Even though I don't know how to fold it
Suatu saat pasti akan berhasil lalu terbang
One day it will definitely succeed and then fly
Kekuatan harapan yang menerbangkannya
The power of hope that makes it fly
Ya, mari kita terbang
Yes, let's fly
三百六十五日
365 days
Hiduplah bagai pesawat kertas
Live like a paper airplane
Terbang dan pergi, membawa impian
Fly and go, carrying dreams
Sekuat tenaga dengan hembusan angin
As strong as possible with the gust of wind
Terus melaju terbang
Continue to race and fly
Jangan bandingkan jarak terbangnya
Don't compare its flight distance
Tapi bagaimana dan apa yang dilalui
But how and what it went through
Karena itulah satu hal yang penting
Because that's the one thing that's important
Selalu sesuai kata hati
Always follow your heart
三百六十五日
365 days
Ayo terbanglah
Let's fly
Coba terbang
Try to fly
Ayo terbanglah, coba terbanglah...
Come on, fly, try flying...
Ayo terbanglah...
Come on, fly...
Coba terbanglah!
Try flying!
Aku dapet!
I got it!
Akhirnya!
Finally!
Yadda! Akhirnya!
No! Finally!
Akhirnya ya Pia, collab kecil-kecilan kita gak kecil, udah jadi besar guys.
Finally, Pia, our small collab isn't small anymore, it's become big, guys.
Yay finally!
Oh my god!
Jadi ya terima kasih sudah mengundang saya Senpai.
So yeah, thank you for inviting me, Senpai.
Wih Senpai! Ya Senpai sudah ulang tahun yang keberapa Senpai?
Wow, Senpai! So Senpai, which birthday is it now, Senpai?
Enam!
Six!
Tapi kok belum lulus-lulus juga.
But why haven't you graduated yet?
Hush hush hush! Daripada gitu mending jikoshoukai dulu. Jiko jiko jiko!
Hush hush hush! Instead of that, better do a self-introduction first. Intro intro intro!
Ahem... We are on fire!
Semangat membara yang menghangatkan hari-harimu.
A burning spirit that warms your days.
Halo aku Fiametta Leo dari JKT48V Virtual Generasi Pertama. Halo semuanya!
Hello, I'm Fiametta Leo from JKT48V Virtual First Generation. Hello everyone!
Wih Pia!
Wow, Pia!
Oh my god yes! Gila kita pertama.
Oh my god yes! Crazy, we're the first.
By the way aku... aku nyadar sesuatu tau gak?
By the way, I... I realized something, you know?
Apa?
What?
Hah! Sorry, so basically buat kalian yang bilang aku lebih pendek.
Hah! Sorry, so basically for those of you who said I was shorter...
Now you guys see.
Halah dikit doang.
Hah, just a little bit.
Hah! Dikit doang means everything to me you know.
Hah! Just a little bit means everything to me, you know.
Means everything.
No no no no no.
Tingginya berapa?
How tall are you?
Uh oke duduk aja yuk.
Uh, okay, let's just sit down.
Yeah well for your information uh gak banyak kok, paling 18 centimeter.
Yeah well, for your information, uh, it's not much, at most 18 centimeters.
Tapi tapi kakiku gak nyampe.
But, but my feet don't reach.
See? Oh my god guys, dia tuh emang...
See? Oh my god guys, she really is...
Look at that, ngambang cuy.
Look at that, it's floating, dude.
Bro ngambang for no reason.
Bro, floating for no reason.
Ashiba... ashiba todokanai.
My feet... my feet don't reach.
Pia lucu banget. Pia tuh bedanya...
Pia is so cute. Pia's difference is...
Kore! Watashi! Kore! Mite! Todokanai!
This! Me! This! Look! It doesn't reach!
Todokanai.
It doesn't reach.
Jadi ya itulah lagu ini ya.
So yeah, that was that song.
By the way koreografinya Fritz-san.
By the way, the choreography is by Fritz-san.
Aku dikasih tau sama Pia.
I was told by Pia.
Pia-kara oshiete moratta.
Pia taught me.
Koh, wah hai, kore itu favorit banget gak sih?
This, wow yes, isn't this like a total favorite?
Oh iya.
Oh yeah.
Coba one more gimana gimana? Gimmick?
Try one more, how was it? The gimmick?
Ah! Lucu banget! Kawaii!
Ah! So cute! Kawaii!
Aih kawaii, lucu banget kan?
Aih kawaii, so cute, right?
Guys tolong don't judge me.
Guys, please don't judge me.
Don't judge me. We're learning okay? We're learning.
Ya learning. Jadi kalau ada yang apa apa apa ya ke Pia.
Yes, learning. So if there's anything, just go to Pia.
Gak gitu ya! Gak gitu!
It's not like that! Not like that!
Anyway, what is this?
Karena kamu mau ke sini aku prepare ini.
Because you were coming here, I prepared this.
Really? Is this like for me?
Iya. Coba coba.
Yes. Try it.
Jiko jiko gimana? We are on fire!
How's the intro? We are on fire!
I'm so honored guys.
Hmm... bau gue.
Hmm... smells like me.
Sorry sorry sorry.
Jadi kalau kalian penasaran ini baunya Pia kayak gini guys.
So if you're curious, this is what Pia smells like, guys.
Iya bau arang. Bau abu.
Yes, the smell of charcoal. The smell of ash.
Bau arang tuh bau gue cuy.
The smell of charcoal is my smell, dude.
Ih lucu banget tapi oh my god.
It's so cute though, oh my god.
Kore wa lucu lucu.
This is so cute.
Hah! Iofi, aku suka banget kak.
Hah! Iofi, I love it so much.
Nggak mau pulang boleh nggak? Bawa pulang?
Can I not go home? Take it home?
Atau gue di sini, gue jadi tukang kabel juga nggak apa-apa deh.
Or I'll stay here, I'll even be a cable tech, that's fine.
Serius nih?
Are you serious?
Tapi iya makasih ya untuk manajernya Pia sudah meminjamkan saya Pia.
But yeah, thanks to Pia's manager for lending me Pia.
Arigato buat staff-san, M-chan arigato.
Thanks to the staff, M-chan thanks.
Arigato. Iya oh my god I cannot really...
Thanks. Yeah, oh my god I cannot really...
Oh oshiku. Akhirnya aku bisa manggil kamu tau gak?
Oh, my oshi. Finally I can call you, you know?
Hah! Aku tuh guys waktu pertama kali dibilang aku mau invite kamu.
Hah! You know guys, when I was first told I'm gonna invite you...
Aku kayak... Nani?
I was like... What?
Wah! Aku ke manajerku kayak...
Wah! I went to my manager like...
Kalau bisa kupegang kayak wah gitu.
If I could hold them, I'd be like "whoa".
Wah! Aku diundang sama oshiku gitu.
Whoa! I was invited by my oshi.
Iya begitu tapi ya...
Yeah, like that, but yeah...
Tapi aku walaupun excited harus pulang bro.
But even though I'm excited, I have to go home, bro.
Oh iya bener.
Oh yeah, that's right.
Oh thank you for coming. Arigato.
Oh, thank you for coming. Thank you.
You know enjoy the rest of the show.
I will watch from there.
Oke siap.
Okay, ready.
Itte kimasu. Bye bye Pia!
I'm going. Bye bye Pia!
Arigato! Thank you!
Thank you! Thank you!
Yuhuu... Obisa!
Kita sudah di penghujung acara nih guys.
We're at the end of the show now, guys.
Tapi sebelum kita ke akhir acara, aku akan berterima kasih dulu.
But before we end the show, I want to say some thanks first.
Terima kasih sudah datang. Mwah!
Thank you for coming. Mwah!
Reine-sama arigato, Rika-sama arigato.
Reine-sama thank you, Rika-sama thank you.
Rio-kun mo arigato, Pia juga terima kasih.
Rio-kun also thank you, Pia also thank you.
Dan... dan...
And... and...
Semua, terima kasih semuanya!
Everyone, thank you everyone!
Ya akhirnya ya, Iofi's Birthday Celebration 2025 sudah di penghujung acara.
Yes, finally, Iofi's Birthday Celebration 2025 has reached the end of the show.
Tapi jangan skip Ads dulu!
But don't skip the ads yet!
Sebelum berakhir aku punya sesuatu untuk kalian.
Before it ends, I have something for you.
Dewa, Birthday Goods... Tada! Boom!
Now, the Birthday Goods... Tada! Boom!
Hai! Iofi's Birthday 2025! Kita punya 3 merch dan sesuatu yang spesial dan voice.
Hi! Iofi's Birthday 2025! We have 3 merch, something special, and a voice pack.
Mari kita lihat ya. Tantan!
Let's take a look. Tantan!
Hai! ioDreaming Blanket! I'll keep you warm 24/7.
Hi! ioDreaming Blanket! I'll keep you warm 24/7.
イオフィが暖かく包んであげるよ。こうやって、ギュッとね！暖かいからね。
Iofi will wrap you up warmly. Like this, tightly! Because it's warm.
Jadi kalau kalian aduh dingin, perlu ditemani hangat, ini aku akan menemani malam-malammu yang dingin.
So if you're cold and need warm company, I'll accompany your cold nights.
で、今年もイラストは夜ノみつきママ！ありがとう！皆様のママありがとう！
And the illustration this year is by Yoru no Mitsuki-mama again! Thank you! Thank you to everyone's mama!
Lucu kali, fuwafuwa, kawaii.
It's so cute, fluffy, and lovely.
Eh tapi kalau udah ada blanket berarti kurang apa sih?
But if you already have a blanket, what's missing?
Next! We have this one! Sweet Dreams Pillow Cover! Syaa!
Jadi ini selain... Tapi kayaknya kepala kalian bisa pas buat di...
So this is besides... But it seems your head can fit right...
Basically, it's so fluffy, it's so comfy. You can place your head right in... yeah!
Basically, it's so fluffy and comfy. You can place your head right in... yeah!
あの、これいいでしょ、こうやって。そうそう。
Um, this is good, right? Like this. Yes, yes.
でもでもでも、イオフィに夢中すぎてちょっと時間忘れちゃう。あ、やばいどうしようって言う時はこちらです！
But but but, if you're too obsessed with Iofi and forget the time... 'Oh no, what should I do?' In those times, it's this!
Hai! Jadi kalian kalau punya ini nggak akan lupa waktu.
Hi! So if you have this, you won't forget the time.
Aduh aku terlalu fokus sama Iofi, aku lupa waktu. Oh my god, ini!
Oh, I'm too focused on Iofi, I forgot the time. Oh my god, this!
So you won't really forget about time while thinking about me. Yeah!
So you won't really forget the time while thinking about me. Yeah!
可愛いでしょ。はい！あ、でもでもでも、次次次次... 次はなんだなんだ？あ、こちらです！はい！どうぞ！
Cute, right? Yes! Oh, but but but, next next next next... what's next? Ah, it's this! Here you go!
Gini kita bisa ketemu di dalam mimpi. 'Dream Rendezvous'.
This way, we can meet in a dream. 'Dream Rendezvous'.
So you will be meeting me in a dream.
So you'll be meeting me in a dream.
そう、夢でも会えるように、このボイスを聞いてね！はい！
Yes, so we can meet in dreams, please listen to this voice pack! Yes!
ではあの、日本語、インドネシア語と英語三つです！はい！ぜひ聞いてね！
It's in three languages: Japanese, Indonesian, and English! Please listen to it!
ででで、今年が新しいのよ、新しいの出てくるのよ。
And and and, there's something new this year, something new is coming out.
There's gonna be something new this year and this is it! Pam!
There's going to be something new this year, and this is it! Bam!
The purchase of Birthday Merch Set comes with a bonus that can be used in the Hololive Official Card Game! Yeah!
The purchase of the Birthday Merch Set comes with a bonus for the Hololive Official Card Game! Yeah!
Ini sebagai bonus pemberian full set premium. Premium merchandise.
This is a bonus for the premium full set. Premium merchandise.
Akan tambahan bonus kartu yang bisa kalian pakai di gamenya official Hololive, guys! Yes!
There will be an additional bonus card you can use in the official Hololive game, guys! Yes!
You can actually use it on the game. Yeah!
You can actually use it in the game. Yeah!
これさ、大会とかで使ったらさ、めっちゃ自慢できますよ。こうやって、「うわ！これがイオフィの限定の誕生日グッズから出たんや！」って。
If you use this in a tournament, you can really brag about it. Like, 'Whoa! This came from Iofi's limited birthday goods!'
でもまあ、お守りとしてもね、ここに置いてても大丈夫ですよ。イオフィがここにいるから。
But well, even as a lucky charm, it's fine to just keep it here. Because Iofi is here.
Yeah! Jadi ini bonus bisa dipakai di kartu ya, di gamenya. Oshi Holomen Card.
Yeah! So this bonus can be used for the card game. Oshi Holomen Card.
Tapi kartunya hari ini yang ini sayang sekali baru ada bahasa Jepangnya jadi mohon pengertiannya ya.
But unfortunately, this card is currently only available in Japanese, so please understand.
Untuk detail kartu dan cara bermain bisa dicek di homepage. Begitu guys, terima kasih.
Card details and how to play can be checked on the homepage. That's it guys, thank you.
Dan kita sudah sampai di penghujung... acara.
And we've reached the very end... of the show.
Jadi karena tahun lalu kita udah dengar 'Here I Am' yang biasa, nah tahun ini aku punya yang spesial untuk kalian.
Since we heard the regular 'Here I Am' last year, I have something special for you this year.
'Here I Am' full Bahasa Indonesia. Ah! 'Here I Am' Indonesian version.
'Here I Am' full Indonesian version. Ah! 'Here I Am' Indonesian version.
でもそれはメンバーシップ限定です。メイン限限定で 'Here I Am' インドネシア語バージョン後で歌います。はい！
But that's for membership only. I'll sing the Indonesian version of 'Here I Am' later, exclusively for members. Yes!
Jadi habis ini akan... apa ya, aku akan ketemu kalian di membership. Oke?
So after this... well, I'll see you in the membership stream. Okay?
では、本当の本当の本当の最後の曲になります。はい！
Now, it's time for the truly, truly, truly last song. Yes!
This will be my last song for tonight.
I hope you're ready. This last song will be... 'Kokoro no Sakamichi'. Shuwa de.
I hope you're ready. This last song will be... 'Kokoro no Sakamichi'. With sign language.
何度も苦しい思いをした
I've been through pain more times than I can say
何度も悲しい思いもした
I've felt the sorrow that wouldn't go away
今日までたくさん歩いてきた
Step by step, I've made it here today
心の坂道を
Up the hill where my feelings lay
歩きなれた帰り道
I tripped and fell on the road I always take
突然転んだ
Caught off guard, like a sudden break
不意打ちみたいで まるで裏切られた気分
It hit me like a stab in the back
破れたジーンズと心の隙間に
In torn-up jeans and a heart with a crack
冷たい風が抜ける
The cold wind gently passes through
小石蹴飛ばして一歩踏み出す時
The moment I took a single step ahead
君がいてくれた
I found you standing there instead
何度も苦しい思いをした
I've been through pain more times than I can say
何度も悲しい思いもした
I've felt the sorrow that wouldn't go away
今日までたくさん歩いてきた
Step by step, I've made it here today
心の坂道は
Up the hill where my feelings lay
君がいたから
Because you were there for me...
強くなれた
I found the strength to be
傷だらけである坂も歩けた
Even with scars, I climbed that hill with ease
君がいるから
Because you're here with me...
歩いていけるさ
I know I'll keep walking free
涙の跡を残さないで
Leaving no tears for the world to see
あの日君は言っていた
That day, you said to me
本当の強さは
True strength is...
泣いてもまた笑えることだよ
being able to cry, then smile again, you know?
何度も苦しい思いをした
I've been through pain more times than I can say
何度も悲しい思いもした
I've felt the sorrow that wouldn't go away
今日までたくさん歩いてきた
Step by step, I've made it here today
心の坂道は
Up the hill where my feelings lay
君がいたから
Because you were there for me...
強くなれた
I found the strength to be
傷だらけである坂も歩けた
Even with scars, I climbed that hill with ease
君がいるから
Because you're here with me...
歩いていけるさ
I know I'll keep walking free
涙の跡を残さないで
Leaving no tears for the world to see
君がいたから
Because you were there for me
君がいるから
Because you're here with me